Guide to the Yale and New Haven Postcard Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale and New Haven postcard collection
1885-1960
RU 687
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.04
(11 boxes)
The materials consist of souvenir postcards of Yale and New Haven, Connecticut. Most of the postcards depict buildings and grounds; some are reproductions of well-known 18th and 19th century views of Yale College and the New Haven Green, such as the Doolittle and Barber views. Also included are postcards depicting Yale athletics, symbols, and student life. Many are photographic scenes taken by Samuel Chamberlain for the American Scene postcard series.
Chamberlain, Samuel, 1895-1975
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 48-A (YRG 48-A), Yale pictorial records and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arrranged by building (region/chronology) code.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of souvenir postcards of Yale and New Haven, Connecticut. Most of the postcards depict buildings and grounds; some are reproductions of well-known 18th and 19th century views of Yale College and the New Haven Green, such as the Doolittle and Barber views. Also included are postcards depicting Yale athletics, symbols, and student life. Many are photographic scenes taken by Samuel Chamberlain for the American Scene postcard series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Accession 2016-A-014 was gift of David A. Northrop, 2015.
New Haven (Conn.) -- Pictorial works; Postcards; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students
- Postcards, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The number before each entry refers to building code [region:chronology].
  - Yale buildings and residences
    - General, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - 1914-1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1930's (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1: old Campus, general views
    - Black and white views, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Colored views, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Oversized, Undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1907-1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1920's (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1930's (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1960's (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1:0 Yale College
    - 1786 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Doolittle view, 1807 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - College and State House (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - circa 1835 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Barber view (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1843 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - circa 1850 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - circa 1861 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1:2 Connecticut Hall
    - 1901-1914 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1940-1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1:5 Old Brick Row, circa 1861 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1:17 Old Library
    - Dwight Chapel (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1:19 Alumni Hall (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1:20 Street Hall (School of Fine Arts) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1:22 Yale Fence, Oakford print, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1:23 Farnam Hall (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 1:24 Durfee Hall (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 1:25 Battell Chapel (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 1:26 Pierson Statue (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 1:27 Silliman Statue (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 1:28 Dwight Hall (Old) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 1:29 Lawrance Hall (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 1:30 Chittenden Hall (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 1:31 Osborn Hall
    - Black and white views (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Black and white views (cont'd) (Box 9)
    - Colored views (Box 2, Folder 38-39)
    - Colored views (cont'd) (Box 9)
  - 1:32 Welch Hall (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 1:33 Vanderbilt Hall
    - Black and white views (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Colored views (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 1:34 Whitman Memorial Gateway (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 1:35 Phelps Gateway & Hall (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - 1:36 Woolsey Statue (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 1:39 Linsley-Chittenden, circa 1905 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 1:40 Wright Hall (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - 1:42 Nathan Hale Statue (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - 1:42 McClellan Hall (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - 1:44 Bingham Hall (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - 2:3 (Old) Medical School, circa 1900 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - 3:4 Wolf's Head (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - 3:25 Davenport College
    - Black and white views (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Colored views (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - 3:25 Pierson College (Box 2, Folder 55-56)
  - 4:1 Skull & Bones Society (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - 4:2 Herrick Hall (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - 4:3 Peabody Museum (Old) (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - 4:4 (Old) Sloane Laboratory (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - 4:9 Kent & Sloane Laboratories (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - 4:14 Pierson Hall (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - 4:27 Delta Kappa Epsilon (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - 4:48 Memorial Quadrangle
    - General (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Branford College (Box 3, Folder 65-66)
    - Saybrook College (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Harkness Tower (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - 4:34 Jonathan Edwards College (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - 4:37 Art Gallery (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - 4:41 Library Street (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - 5:10 Hall of Graduate Studies (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - 5:17 Ezra Stiles College (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - 6:16 Payne Whitney Gymnasium (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - 7:3 Zeta Psi (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - 7:4 University Gymnasium, circa 1900 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - 7:5 Carnegie Swimming Pool (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - 7:31 Sterling Memorial Library
    - Exterior views (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Librarian's Court & fountain (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Interior views (Box 4, Folder 80-81)
  - 7:36 Trumbull College (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - 8:16 Sterling Law Buildings
    - General (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Courtyard (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - 9:0 Berkeley Oval (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - 9:2 East Divinity Hall (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - 9:3 Marquand Chapel (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - 9:13 White Hall (Box 4, Folder 87A)
  - 9:19 Lampson Lyceum & Hall (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - 9:23 Porter Gateway (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - 9:24 Sprague Hall (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - 9:33 Harkness Hall (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - 9:34 Calhoun College (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - 9:35 Berkeley College (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - 9:36 Cross Campus Library (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - 10:0 Hewitt Quadrangle (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - 10:1 Scroll & Keys Society (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - 10:13 Bicentennial Buildings
    - General (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - University Dining Hall (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Memorial Hall (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Woolsey Hall (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - 10:14 Book and Snake Society (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - 10:18 Woodbridge Hall (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - 10:24 Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - 11:3 Hendrie Hall (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - 11:4 Graduate Club (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - 11:6 Elizabethan Club (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - 11:9 Yale University Press (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - 11:19 Stoeckel Hall (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - 11:20 451 College Street (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - 12:1 (Old) St. Anthony Hall (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - 12:7 Byers Hall (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - 12:8 Vanderbilt Scientific Hall (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - 12:26 Timothy Dwight College (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - 13: General views (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - 13:1 South Sheffield Hall (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - 13:7 Kirtland Hall (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - 13:8 Leet Oliver Memorial Hall (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - 13:16 Sterling-Sheffield-Strathcona Hall (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - 14:3 Berzeliun (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - 14:9 Alpha Delta Phi (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - 14:10 The Colony (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - 14:11 The Cloister (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - 14:22 St. Elmo (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - 15:2 Hammond Laboratory (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - 16:5 Wolf's Head (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - 19:2 Marsh Hall (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - 19:17 Ingalls Rink (Box 5, Folder 127)
  - 19:19 Greeley Memorial Laboratory (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - 20: Hillhouse Avenue (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - 20: Tennis Courts (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - 20:1 (New) Sloane Laboratory (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - 20:5 Sterling Chemistry Laboratory (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - 20:6 (New) Peabody Museum (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - 20:6 Bingham Oceanographic & Ornithological Laboratory (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - 20:11 Sachem's Wood (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - 20:14 Gibbs Laboratory (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - 20:19 Kline Geology Laboratory (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - 20:23 Kline Biology Tower (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - 21:6 Sterling Divinity Quadrangle (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - 22: Aerial (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - 22:50 Sterling Hall of Medicine (Box 6, Folder 141)
  - 22:50 Institute of Human Relations (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - 22:50 Medical School Library (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - 22:154 New Haven Hospital (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - 22:167 Epidemiology & Public Health (Box 6, Folder 145)
  - 25:1 Yale Field (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - 25:2 Yale Bowl (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - 25:3 Yale Armory (Box 6, Folder 147a)
  - 25:6 Walter Camp Gate (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - 26:2 Yale Boat House (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - 26:3 Gale's Ferry Boat House (Box 6, Folder 150)
  - 27:27 Yale 1701:Branford (Samuel Russell House) (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - 27:32 Mory's "Temple Bar" (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - 27:33 Saybrook site (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - 27:34 Wrexham, Wakes parish Church (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - 97:3 Tapping Reeve House, Litchfield, CT (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - Exhibits/Collections
    - Yale Art Gallery (Box 7, Folder 156-160)
    - Musical Instruments (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Peabody Museum (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - Yale Sports
    - Basketball team, 1906-1907 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Harvard-Yale regatta, June 1905 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Harvard-Yale regatta, New London, CT, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Yale Crew, steamer leaving New Haven, circa 1910 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Yale-Harvard Crew, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - 1921 Crew (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Olympic Crew, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Football team, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Football, painting of player, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - Princeton & Yale football teams, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Football, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Football, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Football, pre-1914 (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Yale Student life
    - Commencement, circa 1900 (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Dramat (Paul Gilmore as Dick Seeley, Yale 1905) (Box 7, Folder 177)
  - Yale Police
    - James Donnelly (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Yale Symbols
    - "Yale's Favorite Son" (Billie Possum Series) (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Yale Seal (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Handsome Dan with banner, circa 1907 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - "Yale Girl", circa 1908 (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - "Yale Girls", 1910 (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Yale souvenir postcard booklets (Box 7, Folder 184-186)
  - New Haven & surrounding areas (Box 7, Folder 184-186)
  - Aerials & general views (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - Armory, 2nd Regiment (Box 8, Folder 188)
    - Broadway (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - Candee & Company (Box 8, Folder 190)
    - Center Church (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Churches on the Green (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - City Hall Church Street (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - Court House (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - County jail fire, 1910 April 13 (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Duncan Hall (hotel) (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - East Rock (Box 8, Folder 197)
    - East Rock (fold out) (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Elm Street from the Green (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - First Methodist Church (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Fort Hale Park (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - The Green (Box 8, Folder 202)
      - Oversized colored view, Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Pump on the Green at Church & Chapel Streets (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - Harbor (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Hillhouse Avenue (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - Hofbrau House (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Housatonic River (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - Houses (unidentified) (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Judges Cave (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - Karl's Original Bau Haus (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Lake Whitney (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - New Haven Colony Historical Society (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - New Haven Country Club (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - New Haven Hospital (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Public Library (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Savin Rock, West Haven (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - Miss Johnstone's School (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Sleeping Giant (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - Soldiers Monument (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - Lighthouses (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - State House (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - State Normal School (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - Temple Street (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - Tontine Hotel (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - Trinity Church (Box 8, Folder 225)
    - United Church (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - Noah Webster house (Box 8, Folder 227)
    - West Haven (except Savin Rock) (Box 8, Folder 228)
    - West Rock (Box 8, Folder 229)
- Additional material, Circa 1920s-1940s; Accession 2016-A-014; .02; (1 envelope)
  - "Souvenir Album of Yale University", Circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Small postcard album published by Midas and Hahn, New Haven, Connecticut.
  - Postcard. "View across the New Haven Green, showing the Public Library and the Court House, New Haven, Connecticut", Circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Postcard, "Judge's Cave, atop West Rock, New Haven, Connecticut", 1940s (Box 1, Folder 1)